Teiko Middle School
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
（ナレーション）
帝光(ていこう)中学 バスケットボール部
その輝かしい歴史の中でも—
Even amidst their brilliant record,
there was a generation of five prodigies
known as the "Generation of Miracles."
10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた“キセキの世代”
黄瀬(きせ)涼太(りょうた)
Kise Ryota.
緑間(みどりま)真太郎(しんたろう)
Midorima Shintaro.
青峰(あおみね)大輝(だいき)
Aomine Daiki.
Murasakibara Atsushi.
紫原 敦(むらさきばらあつし)
Akashi Seijuro.
赤司征十郎(あかしせいじゅうろう)
そして
彼らを脅かす誠凛(せいりん)高校の—
They are threatened by Seirin High's
shadow and light.
影と光
（灰崎(はいざき)）ミートボールもーらいっ
Got your meatball.
（灰崎）あーん
Damn it, Haizaki.
（青峰）おいコラ 灰崎！
If you're hungry, ask for extra
or go get another helping.
腹減ってんなら大盛りにしとくか
おかわり行けよ
Quit taking people's stuff.
毎回 人のモン取ってんじゃねえよ
I don't mind.
（黒子(くろこ)）ボクは別に構いませんが
Who cares?
いーじゃねーか 別に
You eat people's stuff all the time.
ほら
オマエもよく人のモン食うじゃん
オレは腹減ったときしか取らねえよ
I only do it when I'm hungry.
That's the same thing, Aomine.
（緑間）同じなのだよ 青峰
（青峰）うっ
Also, don't chew so noisily, Haizaki.
あと 音を立てて食べるな 灰崎
It's low class.
（緑間）品がないぞ
（灰崎）あ？
What?
And you should learn to hold your
chopsticks properly, Murasakibara.
（緑間）あと 箸の持ち方を
直すのだよ 紫原
What?
I'm getting caught in your
crossfire, Zaki-chin.
てか崎(ざき)ちんのせいで オレまで
とばっちり食っちゃったじゃん
お 敦の唐揚げも
ウマそうじゃん
Your fried chicken looks good, too.
もーらい…
Got your...
Take a single pickle, and I'll crush you.
たくあん１個でも取ったら
ひねり潰すかんね
（青峰）試合中より
オーラ出てんぞ
You're more fired up now than
you are during our games.
Man, shut up.
ゴチャゴチャうっせーな
I'm always telling you it's
not because I'm hungry.
いつも言ってんだろ
腹減ってるとか
そういうんじゃねえんだよ
人が食ってるモンって
やたらウマそうに見えるからよ
Food always looks so good when
someone else is eating it.
I can't help myself.
ついな
（緑間）そういえば
今日から１人—
Come to think of it, a second year
is joining the first string today.
２年が１軍に上がってくるらしい
Apparently he just started
playing two weeks ago.
始めたのは
つい２週間ほど前らしいが
What's his name?
（黒子）名前は？
Kise Ryota.
（緑間）黄瀬涼太
オレたち以来の
スピード昇格だそうだ
He's the first rapid promotion since us.
（青峰）あ！ オレ
そいつ知ってるわ 前 会った
I know that guy.
I've met him before.
（紫原）どーでもいーし
Who cares?
あー　黄瀬涼太 ね
Kise Ryota, huh?
How unusual for you to remember
a person's name, Haizaki.
珍しいな 灰崎
オマエが人の名前を
覚えるなんて
いやあ… ま カンだけどな
Call it a hunch, but I
think he'll be pretty good.
結構やりそうじゃん
I don't think we'll be friends, though.
そんで—
仲良くは なれなそうだ
さて… 足だけは
引っ張んじゃねえぞ バカども
Now then...
Try not to drag me down, idiots.
（石田(いしだ)）ああ… 分かってる
Yeah, we know.
（森山(もりやま)）随分な言われようだな
He's got an attitude.
Isn't that their captain?
（森山）あいつキャプテンだろ？
（笠松(かさまつ)）ああ
Yeah.
（笠松）クイックネスにたけた
ポイントガード
He's an exceptionally quick point guard.
He's good enough to be a national champion.
全国常連の実力者だ
He's a serious and well-mannered player.
（笠松）
真面目で礼儀を重んじるヤツだ
そんなヤツが
使わざるを得ないほど—
Is Haizaki so strong he has to use him?
灰崎は強いのか？
Though the Teiko Middle School team
and "Generation of Miracles"
（日向(ひゅうが)）今でこそ
その圧倒的強さで—
神格化されてる帝光中学校と
“キセキの世代”だが—
are now exalted for their overwhelming
strength, it wasn't always that way.
最初から そうだったわけじゃない
Their great strength bred
resentment and antipathy.
むしろ強すぎるがゆえ
逆恨みや反感も強く—
They were practically considered villains.
ヒールに近い印象もつきまとってた
Though I've only heard rumors,
あくまで
うわさ程度の知識だが—
灰崎の凶暴性は—
it's possible Haizaki's brutality
contributed to that reputation.
それを助長していた
原因の１つかもな
It's Mine
（黄瀬）う… ぐっ！
何すんスか！
What was that for?
You're stiff.
表情硬(かて)えぞ
I don't know what happened between you guys,
どんな因縁があんのか
知んねえが—
but you just have to play your own game.
オメエは オメエの
バスケをすればいい
ペース乱されんじゃねえぞ
Don't let him throw you off your game.
Yes, sir.
うっす！
Today I'll become her hero.
よし！ 今日は
あの子のヒーローになろう
I'm gonna do my best!
（早川(はやかわ)）頑張いますよー！
ヒバウンドなー
誰にも負けないっスから
No one's gonna beat me to the rebounds!
（笠松）まあ アイツらは
マイペース過ぎるがな…
Those guys are too comfortable
doing it their way.
んぐっ があっ
Their defense isn't bad.
（笠松）さすがにディフェンスも
ヘボじゃねえか なら…
In that case...
（石田）なにっ！
What?
（小金井(こがねい)）速いっ！
He's fast!
（土田(つちだ)）夏 見たときより
一段とキレが増してる
He's quicker than he was this summer!
Damn it!
（福田総合12番）このっ！
All right!
（観客１）きたあ！
Kaijo scores first!
（観客２）まずは海常(かいじょう)の先制点！
Nice shot.
（小堀(こぼり)）ナイッシュー！
That's it, huh?
ああ？ そんなもんか
Give me the ball!
よこせ！
What?
You're not going anywhere!
行かせないっスよ
What?
（黄瀬）は… 速い！
あの頃とはケタ違いだ！
H-He's fast! He's way faster than before!
This is ridiculous.
話になんねえな
うっ 邪魔だ どけ！
Get out of the way!
マ… マジかよ!?
Seriously?
（リコ）味方すら押しのけて…
He pushed his teammate aside!
Huh?
All right!
よっしゃ！
You got in my way and slowed me down.
テメーが邪魔したせいで
踏み込みが遅れたじゃねえかよ
あいつ 先輩に対して…
That guy's his senior!
（望月(もちづき)）んぬ…
Sorry.
すまん…
（福田総合選手たち）
うっ… ぬう…
Kirisaki Daiichi's Hanamiya is a shithead,
（笠松）霧崎(きりさき)第一の花宮(はなみや)は
クソ野郎だが—
but he was the center of his team.
まだチームの主軸として機能してた
This guy doesn't have a shred of team spirit.
チームプレー精神のかけらもねえ
I hate guys like him more than anything.
一番嫌いなタイプだぜ
Let me tell you something.
１つ教えてやるぜ
Huh?
You should respect your elders!
先輩は敬えってな！
（森山）抜かれたばかりなのに
もう！
He just passed him, but he's already...
Don't lecture me, idiot.
説教してんじゃねーよ バーカ！
Who's the idiot?
バカはどっちだ？
You've got something to tell me, huh?
“教えてやるぜ”か
（小金井）福田総合の反撃！
Fukuda Sogo is counterattacking!
（土田）こっちも速い！
These guys are fast, too!
All right! Come on!
っしゃ来ーい！
（伊月(いづき)）スクープショット!?
A scoop shot.
正邦(せいほう)の春日(かすが)が
得意だったシュートだ
That's Seiho's Kasuga's specialty shot.
They made it this far.
ここまで
勝ち抜いてきただけあって—
Their other players are pretty good, too.
灰崎君以外の選手もやるわね
Yeah.
Both teams are going all out
from the start of the game.
（火神(かがみ)）開始から とばすな
両チーム　ただ…
But Kise's hardly touched the ball yet.
黄瀬は まだほとんど
ボールを持ってねえが…
No. It's coming.
いえ… 来ます
（福田総合５番）なっ！
（福田総合12番）これは！
This is...
A scoop shot?
（福田総合12番）
スクープショット!?
（観客１）おおっ　マジか
さっき見た技を一瞬で
Seriously?
He picked up the move he just saw in a flash!
The Generation of Miracles is the real deal!
（観客２）やっぱり
“キセキの世代”はダテじゃない
Try harder.
もっと本気で来いよ
Or was what you said earlier all talk?
それとも さっき言ってたことは
口だけっスか？
（灰崎）やっぱりオマエと
仲良くやんのは無理だわ マジで
It really is impossible for us to get along.
Our styles are too similar.
なんせオレとスタイルが
やたら似てっからな
That's it, Kise!
（武内(たけうち)）よし　いいぞ黄瀬！
This is still within our expectations.
（武内）ここまでは想定内
But why do I feel like something's wrong?
だが何だ？
この違和感は…
あん？
I'll stop you this time.
（黄瀬）今度は止める
（灰崎）えーと…
こうだっけか？
Is this right?
That's the move I just used!
（黄瀬）何っ!?
（笠松）あれはさっきのオレの…
It's like he's saying he can
do anything Kise can do.
黄瀬にできることは
自分にもできる
とでも言わんばかりだ
Is he doing it out of spite? What an ass.
当てつけかよ　嫌なヤローだぜ
His engine's finally running.
（石田）やっとエンジン
掛かってきたか
I hate to admit it, but we
wouldn't stand a chance
悔しいですけどあいつ抜きじゃ—
against a team with one of the
Generation of Miracles without him.
“キセキの世代”を
擁するチームには歯が立たない
Yeah. In for a penny, in for a pound.
毒を食らわば皿までだ
He'll be tough to deal with if
we let him get carried away.
（笠松）どうやらヤツは—
調子に乗せたら
厄介なタイプらしいな
だったら…
In that case...
We don't just score from the inside!
（笠松）ウチの得点源は
中だけじゃないんだぜ
Nice pass.
ナイスパス！
えいっ！
よし！
All right!
Nice shot, Moriyama-san!
ナイッシュ！ もいやまさん！
おおー 相変わらず
あのフォームでなぜ入る？
How does he make shots with that form?
The spin on it was terrible.
回転も きったなー
In fact, it's hardly spinning at all.
というか
ほとんど掛かってないぞ？
His form comes from prioritizing his
own ease of shooting during practice.
自分の撃ちやすさを最優先に
練習してきたフォームなんだろうな
As a result, his shot's unique
timing is difficult to block.
結果それがブロックしづらい
独特の間合いを作り—
It's his own personal weapon.
彼だけの武器になってるんだ
Huh. That's pretty nice.
（灰崎）へえ… いいな それ
Fast break!
速攻だ！
Shit! It's a counter!
（森山）マズイ カウンターだ！
（笠松）戻れ！
Run back!
Quit scampering around, pipsqueaks!
（灰崎）小者がチョロチョロ
動き回ってんじゃねー
えいっ
（福田総合選手たち）ぬあっ！
（黄瀬･笠松）あっ！
I told you to keep giving me the ball.
全部 オレに回せっつってんだろ
He stole his teammate's pass...
味方のパスをカットするなんて…
If he'd joined our team, I would
have taught him some manners...
ウチに来てりゃあ 一(いち)から
しつけ直してやったんだがなあ…
Are you getting fired up
while watching a game?!
まさかの観戦クラッチタイム!?
（リコ）うーん…
いいえ 今すぐにでも
It's not too late to start now!
しかもダブル！
Both of them?!
一旦戻すんだ 灰崎！
Bring the ball back, Haizaki!
ああ？ 寝言こいてんじゃねえよ
What? Don't be stupid.
（灰崎）ふっ もらったぜ
（森山）はっ
That shot
is mine!
さっきの！
What?!
何っ!?
That's Moriyama-san's...
あえは もいやまさんの！
...abnormal shot!
（小堀）変則シュート!?
Impossible!
バカな！
You must be joking!
（森山）そんな… ウソだろ？
That's not possible. He copied my shot
あり得ない
オレのあのシュートを…
after seeing it only once.
たった１回見ただけで…
Do Haizaki and Kise have the same ability?
まさか…
灰崎の能力は黄瀬と同じ…
No.
（黒子）いえ…
（黒子）少し違います
（火神）え？
They're slightly different.
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
Kasamatsu's drive...
（森山）笠松のドライブが！
（小堀）破られた！
...was beaten!
くそっ！
Damn it!
This isn't good.
（武内）マズイな…
今まで手を抜いていたのか
Have they been holding back until now?
They're far better than what we expected
from the videos and Kise's stories.
ビデオと黄瀬の話からの想定を
はるかに超えている
Our team's acting strange, too.
それに ウチのメンバーの様子も
おかしい…
There's something wrong with them.
どこか ちぐはぐだ
What's going on?
一体なぜなんだ！
You're kidding, right?
ウソだろ？ あの海常が
押されてるなんて
I can't believe Kaijo's on the back foot.
何やってんだよ 黄瀬のヤツ！
What is Kise doing?
Their other players are lifeless, too.
他の選手も精彩に欠けるわね
ああ　どっか変だ…
Yeah. Something's wrong.
がっ　あれ？
Huh?
Moriyama missed an easy shot.
（小堀）森山がフリーで外した
First Kasamatsu,
now Moriyama. What's going on?
笠松といい森山といい
一体どうなってるんだ！
I'm not finished yet!
まだまだあーっ！！
（早川）えいっ！
ふんがーっ！！
よし！ ナイスリバン 早川！
Nice rebound, Hayakawa!
The area under the hoop is my territory!
ゴーウ下はオエの
テイトイっスよ！
やいますよー！
こえかっスよー！
I'm gonna do it!
I'm just getting started!
I never have any idea what he's saying...
相変わらず何言ってるか
分からないけど…
Hayakawa's rebounds are impressive.
早川のリバウンドも大したもんだな
そんなに高さがあるわけでも
ないのに不思議だよな
He doesn't jump that high, though.
It's strange.
一口にジャンプ力といっても
２種類あるからな
Well, there are two types of jumping power.
There's explosiveness and hang time.
瞬発力と滞空力
Kagami, you possess the latter.
火神 オマエはどちらかというと
後者だ
The secret behind Hayakawa's
rebounds is his explosive power.
早川のリバウンドの強さの秘密は
瞬発力だ
Because he's initially very fast,
he reaches the apex of his jump
初速が速いから
他の選手よりも遅く跳んでも—
一番先に最高到達点に
達することができる
before other players,
even if he jumps after them.
Which means...
ってことは…
（木吉）その分だけ有利な
ポジションから跳べるってことだ
It allows him to jump from a
more advantageous position.
Huh. That's pretty nice.
ふーん いいじゃん それ
（福田総合12番）えいっ
（早川）うっ
（石田）うっ しまった
リリースが遅れた！
Crap!
I released too late!
うおいあーっ！！
That's mine.
もーらいっ
Hayakawa!
早川が！
He lost the rebound!
リバウンドで負けるなんて
んがっ！ すんませんっ！
I-I'm sorry!
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
This game isn't going well.
（黄瀬）マズイ流れだ
I need to do something.
オレが何とかしないと
Are you running again?
まーた勝負避ける気か？
ま 別にいいけどよ
Not that I care.
Who said I was running?
誰がそんなこと言ったっスか？
あれは！
That's...
That's the drive into a
rolling one-handed dunk
黄瀬と初めて会ったときに
火神が使った—
Kagami used in his first game against Kise!
フルドライブからの
高速ロールワンハンドダンク！
あいつ…
That guy...
That's mine.
今の もーらいっ
Sheesh. We really are similar.
ったく… つくづく似てるっスね
オレたち
Oh, right. You don't know.
あー　オメエは知らないんだっけな
You said we're similar,
but I'm not a copycat like you.
似てるとは言ったが オレは
オメエみてえな猿マネとは違うぜ
What did you say?
何だって？
All right! This time...
よし 今度こそ！
Oh, no. It won't work, no matter
how many times you try it.
あー ダメダメ
何度やってもムダだ
That doesn't belong to you anymore.
そりゃもう
オマエのもんじゃねえよ
そんな…
No way!
あいつが立て続けに外すなんて
I can't believe he missed two in a row!
That's impossible.
（笠松）あり得ねえ！
ぜってーおかしい
Something's definitely up.
We can't use any of the moves Haizaki copied.
オレらが灰崎にマネされた技—
全部ダメになってんじゃねえか
Kuroko, you said Kise and Haizaki's
abilities are slightly different, right?
（火神）黒子 オマエさっき—
黄瀬と灰崎の能力は
少し違うっつってたよな？
Yes.
What does that mean?
どういうことだ？
Kise-kun replaced Haizaki-kun as a regular.
黄瀬君は灰崎君と
ほぼ入れ替わりに—
レギュラー入りしました
Haizaki-kun was lazy during practice
when he didn't skip it outright.
灰崎君は練習を
サボりがちで—
いつも手を抜いていましたし—
Since Kise-kun never saw him play in a
real game, it's possible he doesn't know.
実戦を見ていないから—
黄瀬君が知らないのも
無理はありません
Like Kise-kun, Haizaki-kun makes moves
his own after seeing them only once.
灰崎君は黄瀬君同様—
見た技を一瞬で
自分のものにする
However, he uses his own rhythm and tempo.
ですが
リズムやテンポだけ—
我流に変えてしまうんです
（黒子）
見た目がまったく同じで—
When players see an opponent use
リズムがわずかに違う技を
見せられた相手は—
a move that appears identical but
has a slightly different rhythm,
they unconsciously disrupt their own rhythm
and become unable to use the ability.
無意識に自分本来の
リズムも崩され—
その技を使えなくなる
Haizaki-kun doesn't copy moves.
コピーではなく—
灰崎君は技を奪う
He steals them.
This is mine.
こいつはオレのもんだ
おあっ
Kaijo
Fukuda Sogo
The second quarter is now over!
（審判）第２クオーター終了！
We will now take a ten minute break!
これより10分間の
インターバルに入ります！
Walk faster.
（灰崎）とっとと行けよ オラ！
（福田総合12番）あっ！
Kise, can you still play?
黄瀬 行けそうか？
I can do it. Let me play.
（黄瀬）行けるっス
行かせてください
I will defeat Shogo-kun.
祥吾(しょうご)君は…
絶対 オレが倒す！
Huh? What'd you say, Ryota?
（灰崎）ああ？
今なんつった 涼太
I said I want to play for
the starting position.
（黄瀬）だからー スタメンの座を
賭けて勝負してくれっつったんスよ
ついこないだ入ったヤツが
寝ぼけてんじゃねえよ
You just joined the team. Don't be stupid.
そもそも練習中だって
オレに勝てねえのに
Besides, you can't even beat me at practice.
What do you think you're doing?
どういうつもりだ？
I may not stand a chance
against the other four,
他の４人ならまだしも—
but I think I'm ready to take you.
祥吾君なら
そろそろいけるっしょ
はっ ナメられたもんだぜ
You must not think much of me.
It's obvious I just don't
take practice seriously.
練習なんてテキトーに流してるに
決まってんだろ
Fine. I'll give you a taste
of what I can really do.
いいぜ… じゃあ ちょっと本気で
相手してやるよ
Are you going to let them play, Akashi?
いいのか？ 赤司
Uh-oh. Kise-chin's getting destroyed.
あーらら 全然ダメじゃーん
黄瀬ちん
いや 初心者にしちゃ
出来過ぎなくれえだ
No. He's way too good for a beginner.
He's just strong.
単純に強(つえ)えんだよ
ムカつくヤローだが
それと実力は別だからな
He may be annoying, but that has
nothing to do with his skill.
More! I'm not done yet!
まだだ！ まだ終わってない！
It'll end the same way every time.
何度やろうと同じだ
モノが違(ちげ)えんだよ
You and I are cut from different cloth.
He wasn't ready for this yet, though.
まあ さすがに…
まだ早すぎたな
I'm going to buy some snacks.
お菓子 買ってこよーっと
We're still in the middle of
practice, Murasakibara-kun.
まだ練習中ですよ 紫原君
Shut up. I'll crush you.
うるさいなあ
ひねり潰すよ
Kise has grown extraordinarily
quickly, though.
黄瀬の成長速度は
確かに驚異的だが…
（女子生徒）祥吾くーん
練習終わった？
Shogo-kun, are you done with practice?
Yeah, sorry. I just finished.
あーワリワリ　今終わったわ
あっ あー！
ちょ！ 汗だくじゃん！
You're drenched in sweat.
すぐシャワー浴びっから
ついでに一緒に入る？
I'll take a quick shower.
Do you want to come with me?
Oh, come on.
（女子生徒）やだ もう
（灰崎）ははっ
That bastard...
あのヤロー…
（部員）え あれって…
Hey, isn't that...
最近できた黄瀬の
彼女じゃ…
That's Kise's new girlfriend.
ん… あれ？ 涼太君？
Ryota-kun?
あー アイツ オレに勝負挑んできて
負けたトコ
This guy just challenged me and lost.
Seriously? Talk about lame.
（女子生徒）マジ？
うわー なんかダサー
つーわけだ
じゃあな 涼太君
Anyway, that's that.
Later, Ryota-kun.
You won't let me have it
for free? Yeah, right.
（灰崎）
何が“安く売ってねえ”だ
The Generation of Miracles?
〝キセキの世代〞？
笑わせんなよ
この程度でよく言うぜ
Don't make me laugh.
That's some big talk when
this is all you can do.
チョロすぎて
ヒマつぶしにもなんねえよ
You're so insignificant, I can't
even call this killing time.
He beat Kise?
あの黄瀬が…
完敗？
くそっ！
Damn it!
まさか あの海常が…
Is Kaijo going to lose?
負けるのか？
Preview
Who said he was going to beat me, Ryota?
（灰崎）“責任を持って倒す”
とか言ってたのは—
誰だっけ？ 涼太？
Not yet! It's not over yet!
（黄瀬）まだだ まだ終わってない
（灰崎）ふんっ！
どんなプレーでこようが—
No matter what play you
make, I'll just steal it!
Stay Out of My Way
オレが奪ってやるよ！
I will win, Shogo-kun!
（黄瀬）
勝つのはオレだ！ 祥吾君！